<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>mac on vim, git, aws and other three-letter words</title><link>https://serebrov.github.io/tags/mac/</link><description>Recent content in mac on vim, git, aws and other three-letter words</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://serebrov.github.io/tags/mac/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>MacBook - How to keep it on with lid closed, clamshell mode</title><link>https://serebrov.github.io/html/2025-12-10-macbook-keep-on-with-lid-closed-clamshell-mode.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://serebrov.github.io/html/2025-12-10-macbook-keep-on-with-lid-closed-clamshell-mode.html</guid><description>I am testing the remote desktop to access MacBook and it is inconvenient that MacBook needs to stay with the lid open. Otherwise, if the lid is closed, the laptop goes to sleep and makes it impossible to connect to it.
The solution is to have MacBook in a &amp;ldquo;clamshell mode&amp;rdquo; which is enabled when there is an external display, mouse and the keyboard to the laptop.
To emulate the display (which I don&amp;rsquo;t have), it is possible to use the &amp;ldquo;hdmi dummy plug&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;hdmi headless adapters&amp;rdquo; like this Fueran 4K HDR HDMI Dummy Plug:</description></item><item><title>MacBook - Remote Access from iPad</title><link>https://serebrov.github.io/html/2025-12-10-macbook-remote-access-from-ipad.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://serebrov.github.io/html/2025-12-10-macbook-remote-access-from-ipad.html</guid><description>There are a few solutions to have remote access from iPad to MacBook:
Chrome remote desktop Teamviewer Jump desktop SSH, Mac screen sharing app Some other options I&amp;rsquo;ll start with the simplest - Teamviewer and Jump Desktop.
Teamviewer and Jump Desktop Both Teamviewer and Jump Desktop work well and the setup is easy:
Install the iPad app (Jump Desktop app is $15, but it is one-time payment) Install and run the Mac app Connect from the iPad app to Mac Some notes on teamviewer vs jump desktop</description></item></channel></rss>