<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>kbd on vim, git, aws and other three-letter words</title><link>https://serebrov.github.io/tags/kbd/</link><description>Recent content in kbd on vim, git, aws and other three-letter words</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://serebrov.github.io/tags/kbd/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Touch Typing: Spacebar and Thumbs</title><link>https://serebrov.github.io/html/2024-01-18-touch-typing-spacebar-thumbs.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://serebrov.github.io/html/2024-01-18-touch-typing-spacebar-thumbs.html</guid><description>Traditional keyboards have a large spacebar that is available for both thumbs. On split keyboards, I often see the spacebar key only on one side - left or right.
But what is better? Should the spacebar be pressed by the left or right thumb? Or is it better to alternate thumbs?
A collection of links to touch typing tutors and games.
I was reviewing my layout and I traditionally have two symmetrical spacebar keys on my layouts, but most of ergo layouts I saw use one space with backspace or enter on the other side which is quite a win on small layouts (more functions are moved to thumb keys).</description></item><item><title>Mitosis Keyboard First Impressions</title><link>https://serebrov.github.io/html/2020-11-22-mitosis-keyboard-first-impressions.html</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://serebrov.github.io/html/2020-11-22-mitosis-keyboard-first-impressions.html</guid><description>Mitosis Keyboard First Impressions
I&amp;rsquo;ve received my Mitosis a few days ago and I like it a lot so far:
The size: perfect for the 36 keys layout I use The shape: very comfortable, lowered outer columns feel great for pinkies I wished the inner column, for the index finger would not be shifted up as it is, it causes a bit of extension to use Y and T (not a big deal though) I also think the bottom thumb row is too far, so I am using the top row, having the bottom one without keycaps, so it doesn&amp;rsquo;t get in a way Wireless: probably this was one of main reasons to get it, it is really nice to freely move both halves without having to care about wires An interesting decision here is to use the radio channel instead of bluetooth which gives much longer battery lifetime It requires a receiver to be connected to the computer, but that is not a big deal, also it is cool to realize that your keyboard (QMK) is actually running inside that small board Layout: not sure which layout was there initially, it was QWERTY while the default layout in QMK configuratior is Maltron (I think), anyway, I changed it to my layout, similar to what I have on Moonlander Open source: here is the announcement post, hardware, receiver firmware and keyboard firmware, QMK How it looks:</description></item><item><title>Touch Typing Tutors and Games</title><link>https://serebrov.github.io/html/2020-01-21-touch-typing.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://serebrov.github.io/html/2020-01-21-touch-typing.html</guid><description>A collection of links to touch typing tutors and games.
Online Typing Tutors keybr.com - Typing practice, supports Qwerty, Dvorak, Colemak and Workman layouts typing.io - Typing Practice for Programmers monkeytype.com - a minimalistic, customizable typing test, featuring many test modes, open source keyhero.com - Typing test and lessons The Typing Cat - Free online keyboard typing tutor TypingClub - Learn Touch Typing Free Ratatype — Online typing tutor and typing lessons Typing Scout - Faster typing means more spare time :) 10FastFingers.</description></item></channel></rss>