<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>js on vim, git, aws and other three-letter words</title><link>https://serebrov.github.io/tags/js/</link><description>Recent content in js on vim, git, aws and other three-letter words</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://serebrov.github.io/tags/js/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>There Is No Callback Hell In JavaScript</title><link>https://serebrov.github.io/html/2018-01-19-there-is-no-callback-hell.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://serebrov.github.io/html/2018-01-19-there-is-no-callback-hell.html</guid><description>There is no &amp;ldquo;callback hell&amp;rdquo; in Javascript, it is just a bad programming style. The infamous JavaScript &amp;ldquo;callback hell&amp;rdquo; can easily be fixed by un-nesting all the callbacks into separate functions.
Here is an example:
const verifyUser = function(username, password, callback) { dataBase.verifyUser(username, password, function(error, userInfo) { if (error) { callback(error); } else { dataBase.getRoles(username, function(error, roles) { if (error) { callback(error); } else { dataBase.logAccess(username, function(error) { if (error) { callback(error); } else { callback(null, userInfo, roles); } }) } }) } }) }; The same code with separate functions instead of inline callbacks:</description></item><item><title>JS libraties for charts (links)</title><link>https://serebrov.github.io/html/2013-06-14-js-libraries-for-charts.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://serebrov.github.io/html/2013-06-14-js-libraries-for-charts.html</guid><description>D3.js D3.js is a JavaScript library for manipulating documents based on data. D3 helps you bring data to life using HTML, SVG and CSS. D3’s emphasis on web standards gives you the full capabilities of modern browsers without tying yourself to a proprietary framework, combining powerful visualization components and a data-driven approach to DOM manipulation.
Browser support: IE9+, For IE8 compatibility it is recommended to use Aight. See also tutorials and re-usable charts for d3.</description></item><item><title>Want Scalable Application Architecture? Check AngularJS.</title><link>https://serebrov.github.io/html/2013-03-18-js-scalable-architecture.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://serebrov.github.io/html/2013-03-18-js-scalable-architecture.html</guid><description>The Scalable JavaScript Application Architecture is a presentation by Nicholas Zakas where he suggests a flexible and scalable architecture for JavaScript applications. Here are other related resources:
Presentation summary Presentation slides Patterns For Large-Scale JavaScript Application Architecture by Addy Osmani The presentation is interesting but it also leaves many open questions. In short, the architecture contains following application layers:
base library (jquery, etc) application core: manages modules (register modules, tell when to start and when to stop) handle errors (like wrap all modules&amp;rsquo; methods into try/catch and log errors) enable inter-module communication should be extensible (error handling, ajax wrapper, general utilites, anything!</description></item></channel></rss>